Abandoned artificial satellites.
Tanks jettisoned from shuttles.
（ナレーション）
使い捨てられた人工衛星
シャトルが切り離したタンク
ステーション建造時に出た廃棄物
Debris generated during
space station construction.
This vast amount of junk floating in space,
space debris, is a very serious threat.
宇宙に浮かぶ たくさんのゴミ
スペースデブリは
実は とても危険な存在です
This is a story of 2075, a time in which
this space garbage has become a problem.
2075年―
これは 宇宙のゴミが
問題になった時代の物語
（フィー）テイキング フリー
ゴー 確認
Go for taking free, roger.
Main umbilical, separate.
メイン アンビリカル セパレート
Separation complete.
You copy?
（クレア）
セパレート コンプリート
ユー コピー？
I copy.
Taking free.
（フィー）
アイ コピー テイキング フリー
DS-12, this is Seven.
Now establishing link via Navstar.
（クレア）DS-12 こちら セブン
ナブスター経由のデータリンク
接続します
Datalink confirmed.
（フィー）接続確認
We will be making orbital plane change
using ME to reach transfer orbit,
ＭＥによる遷移軌道への
軌道名変更操作のため―
...so we will separate using OMS
until we reach changeover point.
ＯＭＳで変更点まで離脱
Please verify vector
and window datalinks.
（フィー）ベクトルとウィンドウの
データリンク 確認よろしく
DS-12, this is Seven.
（クレア）
ＤＳ-12 こちらセブン
ベクトルとウィンドウ
ナゲーション
Downlink of vector and window to navigation matrix complete.
- You two have a fight?
ベクトルとウィンドウ
ナゲーション
ケンカでもした？
データマトリックスに
ダウンディック
（タナベ）あっ… えっ？
コンプリート
I copy. Will make de-orbit burn
five minutes from my mark... Mark.
アイ コピー
マークから５分後に 軌道離脱噴射
マーク
So, did you and Hachimaki
have a fight?
ケンカでもしたの？ ハチマキと
えっ そんなことないですよ
No, of course not!
Nothing really happened...
別に 何も
（フィー）ふーん そう
Really?
Man, not these
rations again...
（ハチマキ）
あーあ また このレーションかよ
That reminds me, Yuri.
I was talking
to Tomord a while ago...
（ハチマキ）
そういや ユーリ こないだ
トモルドから聞いたんだけどさ
He says you're always down
in Records Section...
ユーリって よく資料課に…
（ユーリ）ん？ 何ですか？
Excuse me?
Um, forget it.
It's no big deal.
あっ いや いいや
大した話じゃないし
Oh, it isn't? Sorry.
（ユーリ）
そうですか？ すいません
You stare out the window and
zone out sometimes, Yuri.
ユーリってさ
たまにボーッと 外 見てるよな
Do you see something
out there?
何か見えるのか？
Yes. I see space.
（ユーリ）ああ 宇宙が見えます
（ハチマキ）は？ 宇宙だけ？
Just space?
Yes. There is nothing else.
（ユーリ）はい 他には何も
（物音）
（ハチマキ）はっ
（ユーリ）あ…
（ハチマキ）エアコンか？
The air conditioner?
Crap! It stopped again!
やべっ また止まりやがった
C'mon, show a little spirit,
damn it!
おら 根性出せよ こら！
うわあ ああっ
（ユーリ）星野(ほしの)さん 大丈夫？
Hoshino-san! Are you all right?
Ow...
（ハチマキ）ぐあっ… 痛(いて)え…
ああっ また止まっちまった
It stopped again!
Son of a...
ったく しっかり働けよ この野郎
Keep working,
you bastard!
お前が空気 回さないと
酸欠になんだよ
If you don't circulate the air,
we suffocate!
お前が空気 回さないと
酸欠になんだよ
（たたく音）
Hang in there, you piece of junk!
Work! Work, damn it!
（たたく音）
頑張れ こらあ この！
動け 動けよ！
（たたく音）
♪～
Soshite hito wa toki wo koeta yume wo miru
And people dream dreams that transcend time.
♪そして人は時空(とき)を
越えた夢を見る
seijyaku no umi ni idakarete
Held in the depths of the sea.
♪静寂の宇宙(うみ)に抱かれて
tori ya kumo wo miagete wa
As they look up at the stars and clouds.
♪鳥や雲を見上げては
hakanai inochi moyashita ikusen no asa ni
It set their ephemeral souls on fire on a thousand mornings.
♪儚(はかな)い生命(いのち)燃やした
♪幾千の朝に
hikari ga mukau basho he habataku darou
I bet they're taking right to where the light is headed.
♪光が向かう場所へ
♪羽ばたくだろう
daichi wo ima tori yoku kette
Now kickoff from the ground like a bird.
♪願いを放つ時は今
hatenaki yume wo noseta furontia he
Off into the frontier that is carrying boundless dreams.
♪果てなき夢を乗せた
♪フロンティアへ
tooku tooku dive in the sky
Farther and farther dive in the sky.
♪遠く遠く Dive in the Sky
Phase 10
A Sky of Stardust
Thank you.
（エーデル）
ご苦労さまです
（業者）
では ここにサインを
Sign here, please.
You understand, don't you? This isn't good.
（業者）
では ここにサインを
（ラビィ）
ほんとに分かってる？
困るんだよね
有休は
きちんと消化してくれないとさ
You need to use up all your
paid vacation days.
（ユーリ）
すみません そのうちきっと
I'm sorry.
I will try to use them soon.
You say that, but you haven't used
a single day in the past five years!
（ラビィ）そう言って もう丸５年
使ってないんだよ 君は
Oh.
はあ
Why don't you
use any?
なんで使わないんだ？
Come to think of it, you never go
down to Earth or even the moon.
考えてみたら
月にも 地球(オカ)にも降りないよな
The rest of us can take care of those animals
you look after, so why don't you?
預かってる動物の世話だって―
Well, I...
それは…
あ… やっぱり デブリの…
Is it about the debris?
（ラビィ）ほんと ほんと
He's right, he's right! Use your vacation days,
I don't care if it's on moon or on Seven.
月でもセブンでもいいから
有休 使ってよ
総務から嫌みを言われるのは
私なんだからね
I'm the one that General Affairs
yells at, after all.
The bosses have it in for us as it is!
ただでさえ うちの課は―
- This came for you.
（エーデル）
ユーリさん宛てです
上から いろいろ
言われてるんだからさ
- Thank you.
上から いろいろ
言われてるんだからさ
（ユーリ）ありがとう
（ラビィ）目ぇつけられると
私も困っちゃうんだよね
It makes trouble for me when we
show up on their radar, got it?!
Yuri-kun! Are you listening
to me?!
ユーリくん！ 私の話 聞いてる？
Yes.
あっ はい
It's a bad idea to use too many
paid vacation days, but not using them
at all is just as...
（ラビィ）有休ってのはね―
使い過ぎても駄目だけど
全く使わないのも… ん？
Carnations?
カーネーション？
I forget,
is it Mother's Day?
母の日だっけ？
いえ
そういうわけじゃないんですが
No, that isn't what they are for. I was thinking
of putting them up inside Toy Box.
ToyBox(トイボックス)に飾ろうと思って
Gosh, I wish a certain new employee
would also be that thoughtful.
こういう心遣いが
どっかの新入社員にも欲しいよなあ
おーい
Hello?
えっ アイ コピーです
Huh? I copy.
（ハチマキ）ああ？
What do you see
in Tanabe?
（ハチマキ）
どこがいいんだ？ タナベの
（チェンシン）えっ？
You told me to ask her if she
had a boyfriend, remember?
（ハチマキ）
聞いてくれって言ったろ？
男がいるか
So, she's available, then?
（チェンシン）
じゃあ フリーってことかい？
ああ しっかし 分かんねえな
お前の趣味
Yeah, but I can't say that I understand
your taste in women.
I like how she's completely
straightforward.
（チェンシン）彼女のね
まっすぐなところがいいんだよ
Even if there's a brick wall
in front of her?
（ハチマキ）
その先は行き止まりでもかあ？
That girl has enough power
to smash through it.
彼女には
それを突破するパワーがある
That's what
drives me nuts.
それが困んだよ
She thinks that love can fix anything
and everything. It's embarrassing, I tell ya.
何でもかんでも
愛で片づけやがって―
恥ずかしいっての
When you've lived for twenty years, you oughta
know how to bend a bit or make compromises.
20年も生きてきたら
少しは 折れたり曲がったり…
あっ あれ？
Huh?
What?
何？
Nothing. Now that I mention it,
she's been acting kinda strange lately.
（ハチマキ）いや そういや
最近 おかしいよな あいつ
なんか らしくねえんだ
She hasn't been herself.
ああ…
んっ
I did it!
I broke ten minutes!
やった 10分 切った
10分 切れるようになりました
ギガルトさん
I can do it in under
ten minutes now, Gigalt-san...
（ギガルトのせき込み）
Gigalt-san!
Were you hurt in the fight?!
（ギガルトのせき込み）
（タナベ）
ギガルトさん さっきの戦いで…
（ギガルト）
いや いいんだ ケガじゃない
No, I'm okay...
I wasn't hurt.
でも…
（ギガルト）ガンだよ
But...
It's cancer.
えっ
It's already progressed
too far to be treatable.
（ギガルト）
もう 治らないところまで来ている
So I want you to keep this to yourself.
Don't tell him.
だから 黙っていてくれ
あいつには
（足音）
（トモルド）はい 昨日までの分
Here. This is complete
up through yesterday.
Thank you for all
your help, Tomord-san.
（ユーリ）
トモルドさん いつも すみません
（トモルド）
ああ いいって いいって
Don't mention it. You're always
looking after Pople for me.
うちのポプルも 世話になってるし
This is a big help.
（ユーリ）こちらこそ 助かります
（トモルド）ハッハハ
企業秘密ってもんでもないしな
It's not like it's a company secret.
Well, see you later.
それじゃ
I should leave this in the usual
place once I'm done, then?
終わったら
いつもの所でいいんですね？
（トモルド）おう
Sure.
Man... There's a lot more out here
than I thought.
（ハチマキ）たく…
思ったより いっぱいあるな
（ユーリ）１カ所に
これだけ集まってくれて―
We should be thankful that so much
has collected in one spot, shouldn't we?
ありがたいじゃないですか
You're a mature guy,
you know that, Yuri?
（ハチマキ）大人だな ユーリは
Tanabe, bring the Fishbone around.
タナベ
フィッシュボーン 回してくれ
Tanabe.
タナベ
タナベ！
Tanabe!
（タナベ）あっ はい
Coming!
Um, Senpai...
あの… 先輩
Yeah, what?
（ハチマキ）あ？ 何だ？
Forget it.
I... I guess it's nothing.
（タナベ）
いえ その… やっぱり いいです
What's gotten into you?
（ハチマキ）何だよ 一体
Anyway, be careful with your thruster bursts.
The exhaust will scatter the debris.
それよりも スラスターの噴射には
気をつけろよ
噴射で
デブリが流されちまうからな
I copy.
（タナベ）アイ コピー
And don't forget the sun's position.
Gigalt-sensei told us that, remember?
（ハチマキ）
それと 太陽の位置を忘れるな
言われたろ？ ギガルト先生に
（タナベ）うっ…
あっ… ああっ うわあ
What the hell are you doing?!
Be careful!
（ハチマキ）何やってんだ おい！
あっ ヤ… ヤバい うわっ
Oh, crap!
うわああーっ
星野さん！
（タナベ）先輩！
Hoshino-san!
Senpai!
You dumb bitch!
（ハチマキ）バカ野郎！
Where the hell was your head
out there?!
何 気の抜けた仕事してやがるんだ
危うく 死ぬところだったぞ
You could've killed me!
（タナベ）すいません
I'm sorry...
今日だけじゃないだろう
Today isn't the first time, either!
You've been acting weird lately!
最近 おかしいぞ
ボーッとしやがって
You keep spacing out!
I'm sorry...
（タナベ）すいません
（ハチマキ）
謝りゃいいってもんじゃないだろう
Apologizing ain't gonna
make this right!
An office lady being sloppy
down on Earth is one thing,
地球(オカ)のＯＬなら
ヘボでもいいけどな―
...but up here in space,
it gets people killed!
宇宙のヘボは 人殺しになるんだよ
分かってんのか！
Do you get that?!
I'm sorry.
（タナベ）すいません
What's with you?
Is that all you can say?
何だよ さっきから同じことを
（ユーリ）
星野さん もう これくらいで
Hoshino-san, I think you
have made your point.
黙っててくれ ユーリ
こいつは俺の相棒なんだ
Stay out of this, Yuri.
She's supposed to be my partner.
あっ… しかし
Yes, but...
Of all the stupid...
ったくよ
What's going on, you got boys on the brain
even when you're on the job?
仕事中に 男のことでも
考えてたんじゃないのか？
I do not!
（タナベ）違います
（ハチマキ）ああ？
It's not like that at all!
I was worried that you might...
（タナベ）そんなんじゃありません
私は先輩が…
あ…
That I'd what?
何だよ
Fine, suit yourself.
まあ 何でもいいけどよ
If your heart isn't in it, get married or whatever
and go back down to Earth.
やる気がねえんなら 結婚でもして
とっとと 地球(オカ)に帰りな
ん…
誰ですか？
Who's in here?
あっ… ユーリさん
Yuri-san?
Oh, it's you, Tanabe-san.
（ユーリ）ああ タナベさんですか
What are you doing here
at this hour?
どうしたんですか？ こんな時間に
I had forgotten
to put these up.
これ 飾るの忘れてたから
Oh, one of the carnations
from this morning...
（タナベ）あっ こないだ届いた…
What about you, Tanabe-san?
Were you practicing?
（ユーリ）タナベさんは？
練習していたんですか？
No, I'm just hiding...
（ユーリ）ああ…
（ハチマキ）ううっ…
Damn it, I can't believe
how late we are...
もう こんなに遅くなっちまって
残業扱いにもならないし
やってられるかっての
It ain't like we're getting overtime for this.
I can't believe that twerp Tanabe!
タナベのやつ
Look, don't you think you're
being a little rough on her?
あのさ
ちょっと言い過ぎじゃない？
タナベのこと
We're debris haulers, right?
（ハチマキ）俺たちはデブリ屋だろ
ちょっとした気の緩みが
命取りになるって―
You know as well as I do that even a little
lapse in focus can get people killed.
フィーも よく知ってるじゃないか
俺は先輩として…
As her senpai, I'm...
- If it were only that,
I wouldn't say anything.
（フィー）
それだけなら 私も言わないわ
あっ…
What're you so worked up about?
Lashing out at everybody is pretty pathetic.
何 イラついてるの？
八つ当たりは みっともないよ
I'm just...
（ハチマキ）俺は…
うっ…
Give a little consideration
to how she feels.
（フィー）気持ちは認めてやりなよ
Tanabe's been practicing in secret
aboard Toy Box a lot lately.
タナベ 最近
こっそり 練習してるみたいだよ
ToyBoxで
えっ？
Yuri-san, what's it feel like when you
lose someone important to you?
（タナベ）ユーリさん 大切な人が
いなくなっちゃうって―
どんな気持ちなんでしょう
あっ…
Someone who's really important
and you look up to.
すっごく大切で尊敬してて…
でも そんな人が
突然いなくなっちゃったら…
But if you were to suddenly
lose that person...
...nobody can take
his place.
代わりの人なんて いないんです
No one else will do.
その人じゃなくちゃ 駄目なんです
Say that you're going to lose
a person like that...
そういう人がいなくなるんです
And you won't even be able
to say goodbye properly.
きちんと お別れもできないまま
So I want to tell
this other person about it.
だから 私は
伝えてあげたいと思って
でも“黙っててくれ”って言った
その人を裏切りたくないし
But I don't want to betray the person
that told me not to say anything, so I...
I don't know what
I ought to do.
私 どうしたらいいか 分からなくて
Carrying around secrets
is a difficult thing, isn't it?
（ユーリ）秘密を抱えるのって
苦しいですよね
So, that is what has
been bothering you.
それで悩んでたんですね
（タナベ）はい
Yes, sir.
When you lose
someone you love,
（ユーリ）
大切な人がいなくなるとね―
...there's no sadness,
and there's no grief.
悲しくも つらくもないんですよ
えっ
You don't feel
anything at all.
（ユーリ）
何もないんです 気持ちが
You don't think about it.
It isn't good to think about it too much.
考えないことです
考え過ぎるのは よくないですよ
You eventually have to say goodbye
to everyone you meet.
どんな相手とでも 別れは来る
The only difference is whether that time
will come sooner or later.
それが
早いか遅いかだけの違いです
でも…
But...
If you don't think that way,
it's hurts too much.
（ユーリ）そう思わなければ
つらすぎるでしょ？
All right! All right!
All right!
（キース）
オーライ オーライ オーライ ＯＫ
Okay!
Hey, you put Toy Box
in Bay Four, right?
（ハチマキ）よう ToyBox
フォースベイだったよな
Yeah.
You forget something?
（キース）うん 忘れ物かい？
What's with him?
How about an answer, huh?
何だよ 返事ぐらいしろっての
あっ
Thanks for everything.
（タナベ）すいません いろいろと
It is best not to
overthink things.
（ユーリ）あまり
思い詰めないほうがいいですよ
Yeah. I think I can
deal with...
はい 少し楽に…
Senpai?
先輩？
（ユーリ）星野さん？
Hoshino-san?
Oh, you were getting
lessons from him?
（ハチマキ）
何だ 教えてもらってたのか
（タナベ）え…
I came here to put up
some flowers, that's all.
（ユーリ）
私は花を飾りに来ただけです
I bumped into Tanabe-san.
タナベさんとは偶然
いいって 別に
Hey, it doesn't matter
to me.
I don't really have the temperament
to teach people stuff, anyway.
人に教えるなんて
もともと 柄じゃないんだ
That's not true at all.
そんなことは ありません
星野さんは向いてますよ
You're a fine teacher.
Much better than me.
私がやるより
（ハチマキ）へえ～
よく分かるんだな 俺のこと
Gosh, you know all
about me, don't you?
But I don't know you at all, do I, Yuri?
Even after working with you for three years.
俺は ユーリのこと
全然 分からねえ
３年も一緒にいるのにさ
隠れて 何やってんだ
What's with all this cloak
and dagger stuff?
あの… 先輩？
Um... Senpai?
I heard something from that guy over in
Records. I was gonna ask you about it today.
（ハチマキ）
資料課のやつから聞いてさ―
今日 話そうと思ってたんだけど
He says you've been looking for something
week in and week out.
ユーリ 調べ物してんだって？
毎週 毎週
You could've asked me to help, you know?!
I thought we were teammates!
手伝ってくれとか
あってもいいだろ！
仲間ならさ
Why the hell are you
hiding stuff from me?
何だよ 俺に隠れて いろいろとさ
（ユーリ）あ…
You don't have to sneak around
behind my back, Yuri...
コソコソすんなよ ユーリ
Hey...
（ハチマキ）よーす
Good morning.
（エーデル）おはようございます
なあ エーデル
Say, Edel...
If you're looking for Tanabe-san,
she's already done the cleaning and left to fix the
ship's air conditioner.
（エーデル）タナベさんなら―
もう掃除をして
船内エアコンの修理に行きました
I don't really care
where she is.
俺は別に
Yuri-san is down in
Records Section.
ユーリさんなら資料課です
Did I ask where
they were?
（ハチマキ）
そんなこと聞いてないだろ
What is it, then?
じゃあ 何ですか？
Well, um...
それは その… ん？ その花は…
Where'd that flower
come from?
（エーデル）
ユーリさんに頂きました
Yuri-san gave it to me. He said there was a clerical
error and he got one extra shipment.
業者の手違いで
もう１つ 届いたからって
（ハチマキ）
ハッ 言い訳じゃねえのか？
You sure that isn't an excuse?
Maybe he
planned on giving them to you all along.
最初っから
エーデルに渡すつもりで
（エーデル）違うと思います
I don't think so.
In the language of flowers, white carnations
mean "My love still endures."
白いカーネーションの花言葉は
“私の愛は生きている”ですから
You sure know
a lot, Edel.
（ハチマキ）
詳しいんだな エーデル
Thank you.
どうも
（トモルド）ん？
Who's that?
（社員）誰？
ああ 半課のやつ
ほら 動物 預かってくれる
He's in Half Section. You know, the guy
who looks after people's animals.
動物の治療法でも調べてんのか？
What's he doing, looking up
veterinary material or something?
Says he's looking through debris
found by other companies.
他の会社が拾ったデブリを
見てるんだって
へえ
半課のくせに仕事熱心なんだな
For somebody in Half Section,
he's a real go-getter.
（トモルド）ハハッ
そういうのとも違うみたいだけど
I don't think that's why
he's doing it, either.
（マウスのクリック音）
Thank for you choosing to fly
with Oberth Aerospace today.
A compass? Why would you
go and buy one of those?
（ユーリ）コンパス？
何だってまた そんな物を
Oh, leave me alone.
It's a good-luck charm.
（ユーリの妻）
放っといてよ お守りだもん
別に悪かないけどさ
I don't think there's anything
wrong with it.
There's no up or down
in space,
宇宙飛行士がさ
上も下もない宇宙空間で―
...so they say that what astronauts want more
than anything is to know their bearings.
いちばん知りたいのは
方角なんだって
So that's why they keep
things like this for good luck.
だから こういうの
お守りにするそうよ
Hey, you wrote something
inside the lid.
何か書いてあるな
蓋の内側
（ユーリの妻）あっ 見ちゃ 駄目
No peeking!
Why not?
なんで？
I think every marriage needs a secret or two.
Besides, it's a good-luck charm.
夫婦の間にも
秘密って必要だと思うのよね
お守りだし
Good luck, huh?
お守りね
Still, it is rare to see someone who is afraid
of suborbital airliners in this day and age.
でも今どき
高高度旅客機が怖いのも珍しいな
Lay off.
フンだ
あっ どこ行くの？
Where are you going?
アッハハ １人じゃ不安か？
You scared to be by yourself?
I'm getting some coffee, that's all.
コーヒーもらってくるだけだよ
Hey...!
（ユーリの妻）ねえ
（ユーリ）おいおい―
Come on, don't look at me like that.
I'm not going anywhere.
そんな顔するなって
どこにも行きゃしないさ
ああ…
（マウスのクリック音）
（課長）でもさあ 愛(あい)ちゃん
僕の苦労も分かってよ
You need to understand
all the trouble I go to, Ai-chan.
見合いの相手を見つけるのって
大変でさあ
It's hard to find suitable prospects
for marriage meetings.
I can certainly understand parents
wanting to see their daughter married off while she's
still in her twenties.
いや 分かるのよ
娘を20代のうちに
お嫁に行かせたいって親心は
（ドアの開く音）
They say that her younger sister got
married and had kids a long time ago.
（ドアの開く音）
妹のほうは とっくに嫁いで
子供もいるっていうしさあ
でも 適齢期の ああ ほらほら
But I don't know many men who are the
right age. Or even single men, for that matter.
独身男なんて
そんなに知り合い いないしさあ
It wasn't all that long ago when I got an earful
from Ha-chan for recommending a divorcee.
ハッちゃんには
こないだバツイチ薦めて―
怒られたばっかだし
こ… こら！ もう…
H-Hey! Behave yourself!
And Yu-chan used to
be married, so...
それにさ
ユーちゃんは奥さんいたしさ
Huh? Yuri-san used
to be married?
えっ ユーリさん
結婚してたんですか？
あっ…
You remember that accident a few years ago
where debris hit that suborbital liner, right?
（課長）ほら 何年か前にさ―
高高度旅客機に デブリが
当たったことがあったでしょ？
（タナベ）
アルナイル８型事故ですか？
The Alnair-8 accident?
Right, right. Yu-chan told me he was
on board that flight. With his wife.
（課長）そうそう それに
ユーちゃん 乗ってたんだって
奥さんと一緒に
The cabin was torn
to pieces.
キャビンは メチャメチャ
ユーちゃんは
船尾にいて助かったらしいけど―
Yu-chan was in the rear of the plane at the time,
so he survived, but his wife was never found.
奥さんは行方不明に
Oh! I didn't find this out
by snooping!
あっ 別に
探ったわけじゃないよ
先方が勝手にね
The girl's family told me! They said
that their daughter was all for it,
娘さんは乗り気だったみたいだけど
初婚じゃないと…
...but they mentioned that they would prefer
a man who had never been married.
（ハチマキ）
何だよ 隠さなくても いいのに
What the hell...?
You didn't have to hide it from us.
♪～
These are all of the personal effects
that we've recovered so far.
（係員）現在 見つかった遺留品は
これで全部です
If you don't see your wife's belongings here,
then I'm afraid they haven't been found yet.
ここにないのなら
残念ながら奥様の物は…
A compass...
コンパス…
Have you seen one here?
A compass.
なかったですか？ コンパス
Sir?
（係員）はっ？
Never mind.
It's not important.
（ユーリ）いや 別に
Um... Senpai?
We're all done over here.
（タナベ）あの… 先輩
（ハチマキ）あっ
（タナベ）
こっち 終わりましたけど
（ハチマキ）あっ ああ 早いな
Oh. That was quick.
あっ…
Guys? Come back
inside for now.
I'm picking up a cluster of micro debris on
an intersecting orbit, and it's closing in.
交差軌道上に
小デブリ群の発生確認 接近中
Angle of intersection, 71... 72 degrees.
傾斜角 71… 72度
If you stay out there, it might hit you.
You copy?
このままだと接触するかも
ユー コピー？
I copy.
Returning to base.
（ハチマキ）アイ コピー 帰投する
We'll just have to come
back again later.
（ユーリ）しかたないですね
出直しましょう
Tanabe, we're doubling back.
（ハチマキ）タナベ 引き返すぞ
（タナベ）アイ コピー
I copy.
What a pain. Now we will have
to come back and start over.
（ユーリ）
まいりましたね 二度手間に
Senpai?
（タナベ）先輩
（ハチマキ）何だ？
Yeah?
Yuri-san's wife was never recovered,
was she?
ユーリさんの奥さんって
行方不明なんですよね？
Yeah...
（ハチマキ）ああ
You don't suppose that the reason
he keeps doing this job is to...
（タナベ）ユーリさんが
この仕事を続けてるのって―
もしかしたら…
（警告音）
えっ ちょっと ユーリ
早く そこを離れなさい
Hey, Yuri?
Get clear of there!
Yuri! Do you read me?
Debris is heading your way!
ユーリ 聞こえる？
デブリが来るから
Yuri? Yuri!
ユーリ？ ユーリ！
Hachi! Go grab Yuri!
He's breaking off!
ハチ ユーリを確保して
ブレイクする！
（ハチマキ）あっ
Huh? Yuri-san?
（タナベ）えっ ユーリさん？
Damn it, we don't have
time to turn around!
（ハチマキ）
くそっ 反転する時間が
What's wrong, Yuri?!
（フィー）どうしたの？ ユーリ
分かってるでしょ？
You heard me, didn't you?!
You're on an intersecting orbit!
交差軌道にいるのよ
Fire your retros
and lower your orbit!
制動かけて軌道を降ろして
軌道データを回すからね 確認して
I'll send you the orbit data!
Tell me when you get it!
（警告音）
Oh, no...
He's out of time.
マズい もう時間が…
Yuri!
（ハチマキ）ユーリ！
Yuri's hit! We're going in to assist!
Give me his telemetry!
ユーリがやられた
救助する 情報を送れ
Got it.
分かってる モジュール大破
スーツ内気圧 まだ大丈夫
Module, heavy damage.
Suit internal pressure... is still good!
Life pack and batteries are still normal.
Comm system, normal.
ライフパックおよび
バッテリー作動 正常
無線作動 正常
心拍 呼吸
アンステーブル 意識不明！？
Heart rate and respiration, unstable?
He's unconscious?!
I'm not letting him
fall to Earth!
（ハチマキ）地球(オカ)に落とすわけには
いかねえんだよ！
Tanabe!
You ready over there?!
タナベ 準備はいいか
（タナベ）ア… アイ コピーです！
I-I copy!
Altitude, zero-three. Zero-two.
Zero-one.
（フィー）コード 03 02 01
絶対突入境界面 突破！
He just breached the
atmospheric effects boundary!
Wait for us, Yuri...
We're teammates, aren't we?
（ハチマキ）待てよ ユーリ
仲間だろ
Altitude, 120 kilometers...
（フィー）あと 120キロ
We're falling into
the atmosphere!
（タナベ）大気圏に 落ちる
Wake up, Yuri!
（ハチマキ）起きろ！ ユーリ！
Someone is calling me...
（ユーリ）誰かが呼んでる
暖かい
It's warm...
I forget, where am I?
どこだっけ？ ここは
Um...
えーっと…
Hey, don't look at me like that.
I'm not going anywhere.
ああ そんな顔するなよ
どこにも行きゃしないさ
Not this time.
今度こそ
（ユーリ）あ…
ああ…
Yuri!
（ハチマキ）ユーリ！
Give me your hand! Hurry!
（タナベ）
手を伸ばしてください 早く！
（タナベ）確保しました！
I have him!
Way to go!
Fee, plot us a breakaway orbit!
（ハチマキ）
おっしゃ フィー 離脱誘導 頼む
I copy!
（フィー）アイ コピー
Yuri-san! Are you all right?!
（タナベ）
ユーリさん 大丈夫ですか？
Yuri-san!
ユーリさん！
We're losing speed due to friction!
Angle, 5.5 degrees! Output at maximum!
（ハチマキ）摩擦で機速が落ちてる
対地角 5,5度 出力最大
Hachi! I've got an ascent orbit for you!
You just need to...
（フィー）ハチ
上昇軌道 出た そこからは…
（ノイズ音）
（ハチマキ）うっ くっ… フィー
（タナベ）先輩！
Damn! Fee?
Senpai!
All right, fine!
（ハチマキ）上等だ この！
自力で上がってみせるわ
We'll muscle our way up,
damn it!
Please save Yuri...
（ユーリの妻）
“ユーリを 守って”
（ユーリ）くっ…
C'mon, you son
of a bitch!
（ハチマキ）くそったれーっ！
（ドアの開く音）
Can you see him
from there?
見えるんですか？ ここから
ああ さすがに
さっきは冷や汗かいたな
Yeah.
We sure were in a cold sweat
out there, huh?
If Fee-san hadn't grabbed us with the arm, we
wouldn't have been doing much of anything.
（タナベ）フィーさんがアームで
つかみ上げてくれなかったら―
汗もかけませんでしたね
I always thought of Yuri
as kinda standoffish.
（ハチマキ）俺さ ユーリのこと
水くさいって思ってたんだ
But now...
けど…
But now?
けど？
Yuri may be our
teammate and all,
（ハチマキ）
ユーリは仲間だけど―
...but maybe there are some things he doesn't
want us to know because we're his teammates.
仲間だから 知らせたくないことも
あるんじゃないかなって
あっ…
Right.
はい でも ちょっと寂しいですね
It's kind of sad, though, He can only lay out
a single flower for his wife's burial.
奥さんの弔いに たった１輪なんて
I want to leave a bouquet out there, too.
But considering our job... You know?
俺だって 花束 やりてえよ
けど 商売上… なっ？
He's worked his butt off
to bring in debris over the years.
今まで さんざん
デブリを拾ってきたんだ
I guess we can overlook
one artificial flower.
まっ 造花の１本ぐらい
大目に見てくれてもいいだろ
♪～
Mission complete.
ミッション 終了
Returning to base.
帰投します
gutto mizu wo nomihoshi
We gulp down some water
♪グッと水を飲み干し
yuuyakegumo miageru no sa
and look up at the evening clouds.
♪夕焼け雲見上げるのさ
♪今日も一日が終わって
kyou mo ichinichi ga owatte
Let's wind our way home under the roadside trees as another day ends.
♪街路樹の下を帰ろう
gairoju no shita wo kaerou
yaru koto darake de tenpatte
Even if life's so hectic that our tempers flare,
♪やることだらけで
テンパって、
♪無理をして、
つまずいても
muri wo shite tsumazuite mo
we push ourselves too hard, and we stumble,
♪何か必ず
つかんでるさ
nani ka kanarazu tsukanderu sa
I know there'll be something to grab hold of.
♪気楽にいこうぜ
kiraku ni ikou ze
Let's move on without a care in our hearts.
♪素晴らしい人生だから
subarashii jinsei dakara
It's a wonderful life.
♪自分を愛する
勇気を持とう
jibun wo aisuru yuuki wo motou
So let's have the courage to love ourselves.
♪新しいドア叩いて
atarashii doa tataite
Let's take it one step at a time,
♪ひとつひとつ
歩いてゆこう
hitotsu hitotsu aruite yukou
knocking on new doors on the way.
♪素晴らしい人生なのさ
subarashii jinsei na no sa
It's a wonderful life.
♪君も僕もすべての人も
kimi mo boku mo subete no hito mo
You and I and everyone else
♪喜びと悲しみの意味
yorokobi to kanashimi no imi
Keep on searching for the meaning
♪探しつづけて
so just on my way
sagashitsuzukete so just on my way
Of joy and sadness, so just on my way.
Next Time
Boundary Line
But what about Diaper Man?
（リュシー）
…で おむつ男は？
（タナベ）へ？
Wha...?
Um... If you don't mind, could I trouble you for that butter?
（テマラ）あの…
もし よろしければ―
そのバター
頂けませんか？
（ラビィ）
変わった宇宙服だね
What a strange spacesuit.
I think even I could
fit into this one!
（課長）これなら
僕でも着られそうだよ
Would you like to have dinner
with me at Starney's?
（チェンシン）
スターリーで食事はどう？
Love beams, huh?
（タナベ）恋愛光線か…
Zap!
ビーッ
Somebody help me! I'm stuck!
誰か！
これ 抜けないのよ～